<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functional Programming on Andy White</title>
    <link>https://andywhite.xyz/categories/functional-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Functional Programming on Andy White</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 17:50:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andywhite.xyz/categories/functional-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Layman&#39;s Guide to Functors in ReasonML</title>
      <link>https://andywhite.xyz/posts/2019-11-01-a-laymans-guide-to-functors-in-reasonml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 17:50:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andywhite.xyz/posts/2019-11-01-a-laymans-guide-to-functors-in-reasonml/</guid>
      <description>In my intro post I talked about my background and how I started on my journey to learn typed functional programming. I&amp;rsquo;ll again preface these posts with a note that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a background in category theory, so these posts are intended to help introduce things from a boots-on-the-ground perspective. Please feel free to correct me on any points I&amp;rsquo;ve messed up. I&amp;rsquo;m also not an OCaml expert, so there may be techniques or coding conventions here that are not completely correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://andywhite.xyz/posts/2019-10-31-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 21:11:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andywhite.xyz/posts/2019-10-31-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>The world of typed functional programming is a vast, mind-blowing, and often terrifying place. There are so many things to learn and so many rabbit holes to go down, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get overwhelmed, and not know where to even start. For most of my software development career, I operated in blissful ignorance of functional programming - I happily wrote object-oriented and imperative code, mutating data and throwing all sorts of exceptions, and I was actually pretty content with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>